<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="blinded_description">temp</string>
    <string name="blinded_effect">temp</string>

    <string name="Blinded_name">Blind  -  5</string>
    <string name="Blinded_duration">Resist ends (Fail x 3 = 1 minute)</string>
    <string name="Blinded_description">
        You blind your foe with anything from a massive explosion, to a handful of sand, to an arctic blast, to a dazzling flash of light. Pirates, snipers, rogues, and necromancers often make use of this bane in combat.
    </string>
    <string name="Blinded_effect">
        The target cannot see as long as the effect persists. The target automatically fails any Perception rolls based solely on normal sight. Attack rolls and Perception rolls based partially on sight that can be supplemented by another sense suffer disadvantage 5. The target\'s Guard defense is reduced by 3.
    </string>
    <string name="Blinded_powerLvl">5</string>
    <string name="Blinded_attributes">Alteration - Creation - Energy - Entropy</string>
    <string name="Blinded_attack">Agility vs. Guard\nCreation vs. Guard\nEnergy vs. Guard\nEntropy vs. Toughness</string>
    <string name="Blinded_special">N/A</string>

    <string name="Charmed_name">Charmed  -  3 / 4 / 6</string>
    <string name="Charmed_duration">Resist ends (Fail x 3 = 1 minute)</string>
    <string name="Charmed_description">Charms are one of the great banes of legend, wielded by powerful enchantresses like Circe (of Homer\'s The Odyssey), nymphs, psychics, and other characters who control the will of others, not through total domination, but through a magical spell of love or friendship.</string>
    <string name="Charmed_effect">
        The charmed bane can only be inflicted via a bane attack. Damaging attacks that trigger banes cannot trigger this bane. The charmed bane manifests at two levels: minor and major.
        \n<b>Minor Charm</b> - The target is mentally compelled to become more friendly, only changing their attitude toward you moderately. If they are about to strike you, they will restrain themselves - still angry and hostile, but no longer violent. If they want to help you and are leaning toward trusting you, but have some hesitation because you\'ve just met, then that hesitation goes away.
        \n<b>Major Charm</b> - The attacker chooses whether the major charm is platonic or romantic. If platonic, the bane causes the target to consider the attacker their best friend and one of the most trustworthy and noble people they have met in all their lives. Alternatively, the attacker can choose for this trust and admiration to manifest as romantic love. The target is unable to do anything to plot against the one who afflicted them, and will (at the earliest possible opportunity) tell their charmer of any rumored harm or danger coming their way. The afflicted character becomes immediately suspicious of anyone who speaks ill of their attacker. The target is mentally compelled to like and trust you more, depending on the power level of the bane when invoked.
        \n\n\t<b>Power Level 3</b> - You can Minor Charm creatures of animal level intelligence or lower.
        \n\t<b>Power Level 4</b> - You can Minor Charm creatures of humanoid intelligence. You can Major Charm creatures of animal level intelligence or lower.
        \n\t<b>Power Level 6</b> - You can Major Charm creatures of humanoid intelligence.
    </string>
    <string name="Charmed_powerLvl">5</string>
    <string name="Charmed_attributes">Alteration - Creation - Energy - Entropy</string>
    <string name="Charmed_attack">Agility vs. Guard\nCreation vs. Guard\nEnergy vs. Guard\nEntropy vs. Toughness</string>
    <string name="Charmed_special">
        While most banes last until the target actively attempts to resist it, this bane prevents the target from being aware 
		of their affliction and thus prevents them from actively attempting to break free. However, the target\'s true mind is magically suppressed but fights to regain control. As such, at the end of each of its turns, the target receives a resist roll as a free action to break free from the effect. When your target succeeds at a resist roll against this bane, they become immune to all subsequent attempts by you to inflict the bane for the next 24 hours.
    </string>

    <string name="Deafened_name">Deafened  -  4</string>
    <string name="Deafened_description">
        You deafen your foe with a crash of thunder, a deft strike to their ears, or a dark energy that disables their hearing. 
		This bane is common to storm mages, mad scientists, and assassins.
    </string>
    <string name="Deafened_duration">Resist ends (Fail x 3 = 1 minute)</string>
    <string name="Deafened_powerLvl">4</string>
    <string name="Deafened_attributes">Agility - Energy - Entropy</string>
    <string name="Deafened_attack">
        Agility vs. Guard
        \nEnergy vs. Toughness
        \nEntropy vs. Toughness
    </string>
    <string name="Deafened_effect">
        The target cannot hear as long as the effect persists. The target automatically fails any Perception rolls based solely 
		on hearing. Perception rolls based partially on hearing that can be supplemented by another sense suffer disadvantage 3.
    </string>
    <string name="Deafened_special">
        N/A
    </string>
	
	<string name="Death_name">Death  -  9</string>
    <string name="Death_description">
        Utilizing either incredible precision or the power of entropy, you snuff out the target's life force completely. The 
		deadliest assassins and most powerful necromancers are known for such legendary skill at ending life.
	</string>
    <string name="Death_duration">Resist ends (special) (Fail x 3 = Permanent)</string>
    <string name="Death_powerLvl">9</string>
    <string name="Death_attributes">Agility - Entropy</string>
    <string name="Death_attack">
        Agility vs. Toughness
		\nEntropy vs. Toughness
    </string>
    <string name="Death_effect">
			Upon a successful invocation, the target is immediately rendered immobile, unconscious, and unable to take actions. 
			They have disadvantage 5 on all Perception rolls, and any damaging attacks against them count as finishing blows. 
			If the target fails three resist rolls to shake off this bane, they die. The death is permanent and can only be 
			reversed if the GM allows a special mission, use of a rare technology, or long-forgotten magic to restore the 
			target to life.
	</string>
    <string name="Death_special">
        While most banes last until the target actively attempts to resist it, this bane renders the target incapable of taking actions and thus prevents them from actively attempting to break free. However, the target's body fights to regain consciousness and resist the impending death. As such, at the end of each of its turns, the target receives a resist roll as a free action to break free from the effect. When the target succeeds at a resist roll against this bane, they become immune to all subsequent attempts by you to inflict the bane for the next 24 hours.
    </string>
	
	<string name="Demoralized_name">Demoralized  -  3 / 6 / 8</string>
    <string name="Demoralized_description">
        Using your quick wit, intimidating presence, or even a strong display of magical power, you cause your enemies to doubt themselves. A berserker might achieve this effect by foaming at the mouth while a swashbuckling space captain might dishearten his foes simply with intimidating words.
    </string>
    <string name="Demoralized_duration">Resist (minor) ends (Fail x 3 = 1 minute)</string>
    <string name="Demoralized_powerLvl">3 > 6 > 8</string>
    <string name="Demoralized_attributes">
	Agility - Energy - Entropy - Influence - Might - Persuasion - Presence
	</string>
    <string name="Demoralized_attack">
        Agility vs. Resolve
		\nEnergy vs. Resolve
		\nEntropy vs. Resolve
		\nInfluence vs. Resolve
		\nMight vs. Resolve
		\nPersuasion vs. Resolve
		\nPresence vs. Resolve
    </string>
    <string name="Demoralized_effect">
        The affected target has disadvantage on all action rolls.
		\n\t<b>Power Level 3</b> - Disadvantage 1.
		\n\t<b>Power Level 6</b> - Disadvantage 2.
		\n\t<b>Power Level 8</b> - Disadvantage 3.
    </string>
    <string name="Demoralized_special">
        Resisting this bane is a minor action. When inflicting this bane using Agility or Might, you may determine range using the Non-Physical Attack Range table (see Chapter 7: Combat).
    </string>
	
	<string name="Disarmed_name">Disarmed  -  3 / 6</string>
    <string name="Disarmed_description">
        You force an opponent to lose control of an object they are holding, whether through brute force, mental compulsion, a skillful parry, heating the item to unbearable temperatures, shooting it from their hands, or some other means.
    </string>
    <string name="Disarmed_duration">Instantaneous</string>
    <string name="Disarmed_powerLvl">3 > 6</string>
    <string name="Disarmed_attributes">
	Agility - Alteration - Energy - Entropy - Influence - Might - Movement
	</string>
    <string name="Disarmed_attack">
        Agility vs. Guard
		\nAlteration vs. Guard
		\nEnergy vs. Guard
		\nEntropy vs. Toughness
		\nInfluence vs. Resolve
		\nMight vs. Guard
		\nMovement vs. Guard
    </string>
    <string name="Disarmed_effect">
        \n<b>Power Level 3</b> - The target drops an object they are holding in a space of your choosing within 15' of the target.
		\n<b>Power Level 6</b> - As an alternative to moving the item, you can choose to assume control of it. If you do, you are now the wielder. For the wielder to regain control, they can react with a Disarmed bane of their own to counter the effect or make an attribute roll (typically Might) with a Challenge Rating equal to 10 + 2 x the attribute score you used to disarm the item.
    </string>
    <string name="Disarmed_special">
        N/A
    </string>
	
	<string name="Dominated_name">Dominated  -  3 / 6 / 9</string>
    <string name="Dominated_description">
        Though rare, domination is seen from time to time in legendary tales, often wielded by vampires, and sometimes by the most powerful of sorcerers or mad scientists who command legions of mindless zombies, completely enslaved to their will.
    </string>
    <string name="Dominated_duration">Special</string>
    <string name="Dominated_powerLvl">3 > 5 > 9</string>
    <string name="Dominated_attributes">
		Influence
	</string>
    <string name="Dominated_attack">
        Influence vs. Resolve
    </string>
    <string name="Dominated_effect">
        The dominated bane manifests at two levels: lesser and greater. <b>Lesser Domination</b> - The target obeys a one word command until the end of their next turn, at which time the bane immediately ends. <b>Greater Domination</b> - The target's every action and move is under your control. Unlike the charmed bane, characters under the effect of domination lose control of their actions. Their minds, however, struggle to regain control of their own body. They cannot take actions of any kind (except thought) unless it is ordered by you. Every action which the attacker orders the afflicted character to perform which is in extreme violation of their nature gives the target a resist roll as a free action to end the effect. The attacker does not gain special access to the target's mind and so can only order the character to perform actions that they think the character is capable of. Lastly, each mental order that the attacker gives to the target is a major action. However, the order can be a series of verbal commands, such “Attack enemy X unless someone comes through the door, in which case flee”. The dominated creature will continue to obey the last mental command they were given until you give a new command. Only one such command can be active at a given time. Greater Domination has a duration of Resist ends (Fail x 3 = 1 hour).
		\n\t<b>Power Level 3</b> - You can target creatures of subhuman intelligence (animals, some elementals, certain undead, etc.) with Lesser Domination.
		\n\t<b>Power Level 5</b> - You can target creatures of human intelligence or better with Lesser Domination. You can target creatures of subhuman intelligence (animals, some elementals, etc.) with Greater Domination.
		\n\t<b>Power Level 9</b>- You can target creatures of human intelligence or greater with Greater Domination.
    </string>
    <string name="Dominated_special">
        While most banes last until the target actively attempts to resist it, this bane prevents the target from being aware of their affliction and thus prevents them from actively attempting to break free. However, the target's true mind is suppressed but fights to regain control. As such, at the end of each of its turns, the target receives a resist roll as a free action to break free from the effect. When your target succeeds at a resist roll against this bane, they become immune to all subsequent attempts by you to inflict the bane for the next 24 hours.
    </string>
	
	<string name="Fatigued_name">Fatigued  -  5</string>
    <string name="Fatigued_description">
        You cause the target's body to wither and weaken, gradually losing its ability to function until the victim finally succumbs to death. Fatigue may be the result of a necromancer's curse, an assassin's poison, a radiation ray, or similar life sapping effects.
    </string>
    <string name="Fatigued_duration">Special</string>
    <string name="Fatigued_powerLvl">5</string>
    <string name="Fatigued_attributes">
		Entropy
	</string>
    <string name="Fatigued_attack">
        Entropy vs. Toughness
    </string>
    <string name="Fatigued_effect">
        This bane has multiple tiers which are applied in succession. Each time this bane is inflicted, if it is already in effect on the target, the severity escalates by one level.
		\n\t<b>Level 1</b> - The target has disadvantage 1 on all non-attack action rolls.
		\n\t<b>Level 2</b> - The target is affected by the slowed bane, reducing its speed by half. This instance of the slowed bane cannot be resisted as normal. It persists until the fatigue is removed.
		\n\t<b>Level 3</b> - The target has disadvantage 1 on all attack rolls.
		\n\t<b>Level 4</b> - The target loses their attribute bonuses to their defense scores (Agility and Might for Guard, Fortitude and Will for Toughness, Will and Presence for Resolve). They retain any armor, extraordinary, or feat bonuses.
		\n\t<b>Level 5</b> - The target loses consciousness and is helpless. Being forced into a state of rest, one level of fatigue will be removed automatically after 24 hours, unless circumstances prevent the target from resting peacefully.
		\n\t<b>Level 6</b> - The target dies.
    </string>
    <string name="Fatigued_special">
        Unlike other banes, canceling this bane takes time and rest. Each 24 hour period of rest with little or no exertion removes one level of fatigue. If the *restoration* boon is successfully invoked to dispel this bane, only one level of fatigue is removed (in addition to that removed by natural rest). If the *restoration* boon's invoker has an attribute score of 7 or greater, all levels of fatigue are removed instead of just one. A target may only benefit from one invocation of the *restoration* boon to remove fatigue within a 24 hour period.
    </string>
	
	<string name="Fear_name">Fear  -  5</string>
    <string name="Fear_description">
        Through an overwhelming force of physical might or extraordinary power, you strike terror into the hearts of enemies, causing them to flee from your presence. A warrior might invoke this bane by hurling a boulder while a cyber hacker might achieve the same effect by uploading a hallucinatory virus into an opponent's neuro jack.
    </string>
    <string name="Fear_duration">Special</string>
    <string name="Fear_powerLvl">5</string>
    <string name="Fear_attributes">
		Creation - Entropy - Influence - Might
	</string>
    <string name="Fear_attack">
        Creation vs. Resolve
		\nEntropy vs. Resolve
		\nInfluence vs. Resolve
		\nMight vs. Resolve
    </string>
    <string name="Fear_effect">
        On its turn, the afflicted target must use its entire turn to get as far away as possible from you. It cannot use its actions to do anything other than retreat, and it cannot willingly move closer to you while the bane persists.
    </string>
    <string name="Fear_special">
        While most banes last until the target actively attempts to resist them, this bane prevents the target from thinking clearly. However, the target's logical mind fights to regain control. As such, at the end of each of its turns, the target receives a resist roll as a free action to break free from this effect. When your target succeeds at a resist roll against this bane, they become immune to all subsequent attempts by you to inflict the bane for the next hour. When inflicting this bane using Might, you may determine range using the Non-Physical Attack Range table (see Chapter 7: Combat).
    </string>
	
	<string name="Forced Move_name">Forced Move  -  2 / 4 / 6 / 8</string>
    <string name="Forced Move_description">
        With a forceful blow, magical gust of wind, or telekinetic push, you move your target against its will. This bane is favored among ogres, telekinetisists, wind mages, super soldiers, and other characters built to reshape the battlefield to their advantage.
    </string>
    <string name="Forced Move_duration">Instantaneous</string>
    <string name="Forced Move_powerLvl">2 > 4 > 6 > 8</string>
    <string name="Forced Move_attributes">
		Agility - Energy - Might - Movement
	</string>
    <string name="Forced Move_attack">
        Agility vs. Guard
		\nEnergy vs. Guard
		\nMight vs. Guard
		\nMovement vs. Guard
    </string>
    <string name="Forced Move_effect">
        The target is moved a distance against their will, as determined by the bane's power level. The ending location is chosen by the attacker.
		\n\t<b>Power Level 2</b> - The target is moved 5'.
		\n\t<b>Power Level 4</b> - The target is moved 10'.
		\n\t<b>Power Level 5</b> - The target is moved 15'.
		\n\t<b>Power Level 8</b> - The target is moved 20'.
    </string>
    <string name="Forced Move_special">
        N/A
    </string>
</resources>